A Guide to the Charles A. Kennedy Papers, 1963-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Charles A. Kennedy Papers, 1963-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1994-018
3.1 cu. ft. 3 boxes
The Charles A. Kennedy Papers consists of letters, newspaper clippings, reprints, reports, and other files on Kennedy's interest and involvement with foreign affairs (particularly the implications of nuclear war) and international students at Virginia Tech.
Kennedy, Charles A.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Charles A. Kennedy Papers were donated upon his retirement as a professor at Virginia Tech in May 1994.
Biographical Note
Charles Kennedy was the first full time professor of religion at Virginia Tech starting in 1967, and he was hired to teach the Bible and Asian religions. He also was the advisor of International Studies from 1972-1979. He retired as the head of the Religion Department in 1994.
Sources: History of Religion Department
Scope and Content
The Charles A. Kennedy Papers consists of letters, newspaper clippings, reprints, reports, and other files dating from 1963 (just before Kennedy came to Virginia Tech) to 1987. Highlights include brochures and pamphlets for international students, correspondence involving foreign affairs with a focus on nuclear war and also a television script that he wrote. Media materials include watercolor prints, film, and songs.
Arrangement
The files are arranged in the order they were received.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
The following materials were catalogued in the Rare Book Collection:
Seeing Expo '70: Guide to Japan World Exposition
Photographic History of Worlds Fair -James Wilson Pierce, 1893
Shepp's World Fair, Photographed by James W. Shepp, 1893
Gems of the World's Fair and Midway Paisance, 1894
The Dream City, 1893
Expo '67: Guide Official
The Ecology and Sociology of the Norway Rat, John B. Calhoun, 1962
Heywood Brown, As He Seemed to Us The Queen-The Coronation, 1953
The Maritime Theme in Second Themple Numismatics, Vols. 1 & 2, J. Lawrence, 1973
The Effects on the Atmosphere of a Major Nuclear Exchange, 1985
Nuclear Winter: Strategic and Diplomatic Implications: Position Papers of Panelists Received as of March 6, 1986 Engineers Forum, Vol. 4 No. 4, April 1986
Repertorio Topografico Delle Pitture Delle Catacombe Romane, Di Aldo Nestori, 1975
Il Cimitero Di Priscilla, Studio Di Topografia E Architettura, 1970
Inscriptiones Christianae Urbis Romae Septimo Saeculo Antiqiuores, Edidit Iosephvu Gatti
Inscriptiones Christianae Urbis Romae, Septimo Saeculo Antiquiores, Edidit Ionnaes Bapt De Rossi, Vols. 1 & 2
Flying Saucers: Mysteries of the Space Age, August 1967, Issue No. 53
Flying Saucers Pictorial: The World's Largest Collection of UFO Photographs
Index Terms
Person:
Kennedy, Charles A.
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Maps, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 1-1)
- Nuclear Winter (4 Folders), 1986 (Box-folder 1-2 to 1-5)
- Correspondence and Writings (4 Folders), 1986-1987 (Box-folder 1-6 to 1-9)
- Extensions and International Programs, 1987 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Correspondence and Writings (3 Folders), 1975-1984 (Box-folder 1-11 to 1-13)
- Speeches and Writings, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Report, 1987 (Box-folder 1-15)
- Correspondence and Lists, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 1-16)
- Lists and Notes, 1969 (Box-folder 1-17)
- Correspondence and Writings, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 1-18)
- Articles, n.d. (Box-folder 1-19)
- Correspondence and Writings (4 Folders), 1964-1970 (Box-folder 1-20 to 1-23)
- Foreign Exchange Students, n.d. (Box-folder 1-24)
- TV Script "That New Breed," 1972 (Box-folder 1-25)
- Community Program Materials, 1965-1966, n.d. (Box-folder 2-1)
- Bank Records, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Reference Materials, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 2-3)
- Q.N. & Abbreviated Derivations, 1968 (Box-folder 2-4)
- VA Humanities-TV Proposal, 1977 (Box-folder 2-5)
- VA Humanities, 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 2-6)
- VA Humanities FNDTN-TV Budget, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 2-7)
- VF HPP- Public Unions, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 2-8)
- Humanities-Photos, n.d. (Box-folder 2-9)
- New Breed Prints (3 Folders), 1970-1973 (Box-folder 2-10 to 2-12)
- New Breed-Info, 1972 (Box-folder 2-13)
- Original Text, n.d. (Box-folder 2-14)
- Originals-TNB-2, n.d. (Box-folder 2-15)
- NEH Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2-16)
- DG/TNB Art, n.d. (Box-folder 2-17)
- DG/TNB-Budget/Personal, n.d. (Box-folder 2-18)
- DG/TNB Script Materials, n.d. (Box-folder 2-19)
- That New Breed Proposal, 1973 (Box-folder 2-20)
- That New Breed, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2-21)
- Danforth, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 2-22)
- Danforth, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2-23)
- Danforth Current, 1971 (Box-folder 2-24)
- The Huguenot Program, n.d. (Box-folder 2-25)
- Sanderson, 1986 (Box-folder 2-26)
- SIMS, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2-27)
- Kennedy, n.d. (Box-folder 2-28)
- 1685-1985 Names, 1985 (Box-folder 2-29)
- CVS, 1984 (Box-folder 2-30)
- Charleston, 1985 (Box-folder 2-31)
- Library, 1984 (Box-folder 2-32)
- Rehearsal for Freedom: The Huguenots, 1985 (Box-folder 2-33)
- Turk, 1985 (Box-folder 2-34)
- WBRA-TV, 1985 (Box-folder 2-35)
- Part II Resources, 1985 (Box-folder 2-36)
- Script, 1985 (Box-folder 2-37)
- Songs, n.d. (Box-folder 3-1)
- Watercolors, n.d. (Box-folder 3-2)
- Films and Negatives, n.d. (Box 3)